<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Prologue on</title><link>https://tntech-ngin.github.io/F23-CSC4200/docs/prologue/</link><description>Recent content in Prologue on</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><lastBuildDate>Tue, 06 Oct 2020 08:48:45 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://tntech-ngin.github.io/F23-CSC4200/docs/prologue/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Schedule</title><link>https://tntech-ngin.github.io/F23-CSC4200/docs/prologue/schedule/</link><pubDate>Thu, 12 Jan 2023 11:05:37 -0600</pubDate><guid>https://tntech-ngin.github.io/F23-CSC4200/docs/prologue/schedule/</guid><description>This is a tentative schedule and will change.
Aug 19 -
Introduction, Social Contract, Expectations - Link to Mural Slides Books - Peterson &amp;amp; Davie, Computer Networks - a systems approach. Labs - Every Thursday, in class Week of Aug 20 - Aug 26 #
Reading assignment for week 1 - Introduction, Chapter 1.2 - 1.5 Introduction - Terminologies, Circuit vs Packet Switching, Layers, Architectures vs Protocols Slides Network Performance, Bandwidth/Delay, Jitter Slides Thu, Aug 22 - Lecture Thu, Aug 24 - Lecture and Lab (Setting up Google Cloud VMs) Week of Aug 27 - Sep 02 #
Reading assignment - Chapter 2-2.</description></item><item><title>Lab 1: Setting Up and Testing Virtual Machines on Google Cloud</title><link>https://tntech-ngin.github.io/F23-CSC4200/docs/prologue/lab1/</link><pubDate>Thu, 12 Jan 2023 11:05:37 -0600</pubDate><guid>https://tntech-ngin.github.io/F23-CSC4200/docs/prologue/lab1/</guid><description>Note: The following guide provides step-by-step instructions for creating and configuring virtual machines (VMs) on the Google Cloud Platform (GCP). Subsequently, the guide outlines the process of establishing network connectivity between these VMs using the &amp;ldquo;ping&amp;rdquo; command. This exercise aims to provide students with a practical understanding of cloud-based virtualization, network configuration, and basic connectivity testing. This lab is ungraded.
Lab Objectives #
Creating two virtual machines on Google Cloud. Configuring network settings for the VMs.</description></item><item><title>Lab 2: Use basic networking tools</title><link>https://tntech-ngin.github.io/F23-CSC4200/docs/prologue/lab2/</link><pubDate>Thu, 12 Jan 2023 11:05:37 -0600</pubDate><guid>https://tntech-ngin.github.io/F23-CSC4200/docs/prologue/lab2/</guid><description>This lab counts towards your class participation grade
Initial Setup #
We will utilize the VMs we created in LAB 1. Open a terminal (can be in your browser or on your laptop) and log into the VMs. Turn in the following (you may use Google and/or collaborate with other students) #
Please submit one PDF with your work. You might find the “man” command to be very useful.
SSH into two instances and perform the following tests:</description></item><item><title>Lab 3: Introduction to Socket Programming</title><link>https://tntech-ngin.github.io/F23-CSC4200/docs/prologue/lab3/</link><pubDate>Thu, 12 Jan 2023 11:05:37 -0600</pubDate><guid>https://tntech-ngin.github.io/F23-CSC4200/docs/prologue/lab3/</guid><description>This lab is ungraded but counts towards your participation grade
Initial Setup #
We will utilize the VMs we created in LAB 1. Log into two VMs. Follow along with the instructor. At the end of the lab, you will be able to create a simple client and server.</description></item><item><title>Program 1</title><link>https://tntech-ngin.github.io/F23-CSC4200/docs/prologue/pa1/</link><pubDate>Thu, 12 Jan 2023 11:09:01 -0600</pubDate><guid>https://tntech-ngin.github.io/F23-CSC4200/docs/prologue/pa1/</guid><description>This is an INDIVIDUAL Assignment (Do not collaborate) Due - Sept 14, Thursday, 11:59PM
Instructions #
Create two separate Python files for the server and client, named server.py and client.py, respectively.
Copy and paste the provided skeleton code into the respective files.
Complete the server code by implementing the missing function calls where indicated by comments. The server should be able to accept connections, receive long messages from clients, process them, and echo back the same message.</description></item></channel></rss>